Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- Hermes Payrhuber (b. 1969)
  Hermes Payrhuber first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2007. They contain exhibition announcements, CDs with images of art, publications, CVs, essays, press releases, an exhibition catalog, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2002-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/hermes-payrhuber
  - Box 45, Folder 4 (Box 45)
- Christopher Peel (b. 1953)
  Christopher Peel was born in 1953 in Nottingham, England. He studied at the City and Guilds of London Institute. He works primarily in paintings.
  Christopher Peel first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain a CD with images of art, correspondence, and an artist's biography. These materials are dated 2009.
  - Box 45, Folder 5 (Box 45)
- Marc Pelletier (b. 1957)
  Marc Pelletier was born in 1957 in Lewiston, Maine. He received a BFA from the University of Southern Maine and an MFA from Syracuse University. He also studied in the UK. His work includes drawing, painting, and printmaking. He also began making collages when he moved to New York in 1983. His work has been exhibited in New York.
  Marc Pelletier first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2006. They contain exhibition materials, a CD with images of art, an artist's statement, a CV, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2001-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/marc-pelletier
  - Box 45, Folder 6 (Box 45)
- Daniel L. Perry (b. 1959)
  Daniel L. Perry was born in 1959 in Ann Arbor, Michigan. He began painting at an early age and has worked as a freelance painter, a set designer, and graphic designer. His colorful paintings span landscape, portrait, and abstraction. His work has been exhibited in a variety of settings.
  Daniel L. Perry first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, photocopies of artwork, photographic prints of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2003-2006.
  - Box 45, Folder 11 (Box 45)
- Grahame Perry (1959–2015)
  Grahame Perry was born in 1959 in London and came to the US when he was young. He received a BA from the University of California Berkeley and later returned to school for an AS in Photography. His work spans street photography, urban landscapes, community events, and night photography. It has been exhibited in California. He passed away in 2015.
  Materials pertaining to Grahame Perry donated to the Visual AIDS archive include an artist's statement, exhibition materials, and a price list. These materials are dated 2010-2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/grahame-perry
  - Box 69, Folder 11 (Box 69)
- David Pibel (b. 1934)
  David Pibel was born in 1934. He served as a Marine and later a member of the Peace Corps and worked as an educator for many years. He is a sculptor, working primarily in woodcarving.
  Materials pertaining to David Pibel include artist's biographies and correspondence. These materials are dated 2017-2021.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-pibel
  - Box 70, Folder 2 (Box 70)
- Hattie Powell (b. 1946)
  Hattie Powell was born in 1946 in Florida. Her work is primarily in painting, which she has exhibited at the Jewish Board Art Show annually. She lives in New York.
  Hattie Powell first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. They consist of an artist's biography and press clippings. These materials are dated 2000.
  - Box 45, Folder 12 (Box 45)
- Fitzgerald Providence (b. 1959)
  Fitzgerald Providence was born in 1959. He studied at School of Visual Arts. He has been a facilitator at GMHC since 2016, helping others make art. His work has been exhibited in New York.
  Materials pertaining to Fitzgerald Providence include Postcards from the Edge submission materials. This material is undated.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/fitzgerald-providence
  - Box 46, Folder 1 (Box 46)
- Ronnie Queenan (1954-2023)
  Ronnie Queenan was born in 1954 in Lubbock, Texas. He studied at Texas Southern University and Glassell School of Art. A painter, he worked primarily with landscapes and abstraction. He passed away in 2023.
  Ronnie Queenan first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2006. They contain correspondence, cards with original paintings, CDs with images of art, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, an artist's statement, publications, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2003-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/ronnie-queenan
  - Box 46, Folder 3 (Box 46)
- Jolanta Rakouska (b. 1961)
  Jolanta Rakouska was born in 1961 in Poland. She is a self-taught artist and primarily works in painting.
  Jolanta Rakouska first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. They contain photographs, exhibition price lists, an artist's biography, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1999-2002.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jolanta-rakouska
  - Box 46, Folder 5 (Box 46)
- Chuck Ramirez (1962–2010)
  Chuck Ramirez was born in 1962 in San Antonio, Texas. His work spans photography as well as graphic design and advertising. He was a central part of the San Antonio art community and his work was collected by the Smithsonian American Art Museum in 2012. He passed away in 2010.
  Materials pertaining to Chuck Ramirez were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2012 by Patricia Ruiz-Healy. They contain a CD with images of art, ephemera, correspondence, and an artist's biography. These materials are dated 2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/chuck-ramirez
  - Box 46, Folder 6 (Box 46)
- Luis M. Ramirez (b. 1970)
  Luis Ramirez was born in 1970. He received a BA in Interior Design and a masters from the Sustainable Environments program at the Fashion Institute of Technology in New York. His practice spans digital and classical art, photography, painting, sculpture, collage, and installation, as well as historical restoration and preservation.
  Luis Ramirez first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain an artist's biography and a CD with images of art.These materials are dated 2009.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/luis-ramirez
  - Box 46, Folder 7 (Box 46)
- Robert Reed (b. 1961)
  Robert Reed was born in 1961 in Searcy, Arkansas. His work includes painting, sculpture, performance, mixed media, and installation. It has been exhibited in New York and Boston.
  Robert Reed first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain photographs of art, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, CVs, press clippings, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1995-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/robert-reed
  - Box 46, Folder 10 (Box 46)
- Richard Renaldi (b. 1968)
  Richard Renaldi was born in 1968 in Chicago, Illinois. He received a BA in photography from New York University. His photography has been exhibited across the US and internationally. His work has been published in six monographs, among other publications.
  Richard Renaldi first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain correspondence, exhibition announcements, ephemera, CVs, press clippings, periodicals, photographic prints of art, press releases, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2000-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/richard-renaldi
  - Box 47, Folder 3 (Box 47)
- David Reyes (b. 1954)
  David Reyes was born in 1954 in Trinidad. He came to the United States in the 1970s and studied art at the American Musical and Dramatic Academy in New York. He works in painting, illustration, and mixed media.
  David Reyes first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain correspondence, calendar submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1998-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-reyes
  - Box 47, Folder 4 (Box 47)
- Hunter Reynolds (1959–2022)
  Hunter Reynolds was born in 1959 in Rochester, Minnesota. He was an artist and AIDS activist. As an early member of ACT-UP he cofounded a sub-group within it called Art Positive. His artwork spans photography, performance, and installation work. His work has been exhibited widely in the US and internationally and is housed in numerous public and private collections. He passed away in 2022.
  Hunter Reynolds first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain postcards of artwork, exhibition announcements, exhibition programs, exhibition catalogs, correspondence, ephemera, press releases, press clippings, periodicals, publications, an exhibition book, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/hunter-reynolds
  - Box 47, Folder 5 (Box 47)
  - Box 47, Folder 6 (Box 47)
  - Box B, Folder 10 (Box B)
- Eric Rhein (b. 1962)
  Eric Rhein was born in 1961 and raised in the Hudson Valley. He received both a BFA and MFA from the School of Visual Arts in New York. He is an activist and has worked with Visual AIDS since the mid-1990s. He works primarily in wire drawings, sculpture, mixed media collage, and photography and often includes salvaged materials. His work has been exhibited internationally and reviews of his work have appeared in numerous publications.
  Eric Rhein first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, CDs with images of art, correspondence, CVs, artist's statements, press releases, press clippings, publications, calendar submission materials, exhibition proposals, image lists, ephemera, images of art, an exhibition poster, exhibition programs, exhibition catalogs, periodicals, a CD with images of art, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1989-2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/eric-rhein
  - Box 48, Folder 2 (Box 48)
  - Box 48, Folder 3 (Box 48)
  - Box 48, Folder 4 (Box 48)
  - Box 48, Folder 5 (Box 48)
  - Box 49, Folder 1 (Box 49)
  - Box B, Folder 11 (Box B)
- Drake Richardson (b. 1963)
  Drake Richardson was born in 1963 in New York. He studied art and design in high school and college. He works primarily in pencil and charcoal drawings. He lives in New York.
  Drake Richardson first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. They contain artist's biographies, an artist's statement, and grant application materials. These materials are dated 2000.
  - Box 49, Folder 2 (Box 49)
- Herb Ritts (1952–2002)
  Herb Ritts was born in 1952. He began his photographic career in the late 1970s and became well known as an art and commercial photographer. His commercial work has appeared in numerous publications and his art photography has been exhibited internationally. It is held in many private and public collections. He passed away in 2002.
  Materials pertaining to Herb Ritts include periodicals. These materials are dated 1996-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/herb-ritts
  - Box 49, Folder 5 (Box 49)
- Jose Rivera (b. 1968)
  Jose Rivera was born in 1968 in Brooklyn, New York. He works primarily in painting and illustration. He lives in New York.
  Jose Rivera first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain correspondence and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1998-2003.
  - Box 49, Folder 6 (Box 49)
- Juan Rivera (1957–2011)
  Juan Rivera was born in 1957 in New Haven, Connecticut. He lived most of his life in New York. His photographs document the New York cultural scene in the 1980s, including his relationship with Keith Haring. He also worked in illustration. He wrote a book about his life in 2007 and passed away in 2011.
  Juan Rivera first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain an artist's biography, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1985-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/juan-rivera
  - Box 49, Folder 7 (Box 49)
- Alexander Robateau (b. 1964)
  Alexander Robateau was born in 1964 in Belize. He works primarily in painting — mostly portrait, still-life, and murals — as well as wallpaper and fabric design. He lives and works in the Bronx.
  Materials pertaining to Alexander Robateau donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain images of artwork and ephemera. These materials are dated 2017.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/alexander-robateau
  - Box 49, Folder 8 (Box 49)
- Daniel Roberts (b. 1957)
  Daniel Roberts was born in 1957 in Newton, Kansas. He received a BFA from Kansas State University. His work includes sculpture, painting, and mixed media work. His work has been exhibited in New York and Florida.
  Daniel Roberts first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain a CD with images of art, correspondence, ephemera, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition programs, CVs, slide lists, artist's statements, exhibition announcements, poster of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1991-2023.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/daniel-roberts
  - Box 49, Folder 9 (Box 49)
  - Box B, Folder 17 (Box B)
- Sandy Lee Robertson (b. 1946)
  Sandy Lee Robertson was born in 1946 in North Carolina. He received a BS in Studio Arts from Winston Salem State University and an MA in art and education from Miami University. He primarily works in painting and drawings and has been exhibited in North Carolina and New York. He has also worked as an art educator.
  Sandy Lee Robertson first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They include correspondence, photographic prints, exhibition announcements, an artist's biography, press clippings, CVs, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1978-2010.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/sandy-lee-robertson
  - Box 49, Folder 10 (Box 49)
  - Box B, Folder 12 (Box B)
- Nevin Robinson (b. 1963)
  Nevin Robinson was born in 1962 in Illinois. He received a BA in cinema and photography from Southern Illinois University and an MFA in photography from San Francisco Art Institute. He has been a photographer since childhood and has exhibited work in the US and internationally.
  Nevin Robinson first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain exhibition announcements, ephemera, CVs, image lists, artist's statements, press clippings, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1998-2008.
  - Box 49, Folder 11 (Box 49)
- Abnel Rodriguez (b. 1964)
  Abnel Rodriguez was born in 1964 in San Juan, Puerto Rico. He studied painting and drawing at the Art Students League of San Juan and the Luchetti School of Visual Arts. He later studied at Pratt Institute in New York and the University of Puerto Rico. He has worked in illustration, translation, design, and editing for Macmillan Publishing Co. His artwork spans a variety of media including painting, illustration, and photography and has been exhibited in New York and Puerto Rico.
  Abnel Rodriguez first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain a photograph of the artist, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition announcements, ephemera, exhibition programs, artist's statements, artist's biographies, CVs, press clippings, calendar submisson materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1994-1999.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/abnel-rodriguez
  - Box 50, Folder 1 (Box 50)
- Nelson Edwin Rodriguez (1972–1995)
  Nelson Edwin Rodriguez was born in 1972 in Puerto Rico. His family moved to New York City and in 1990 he participated in a photography course at the Hetrick-Martin Institute alongside Milton Garcia Ninja and Luna Luis Ortiz. He was a photographer and performer. He passed away in 1995.
  Materials pertaining to Nelson Rodriguez were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000 by Barbara Bickart. They contain event programs, exhibition announcements, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1993-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/nelson-rodriguez
  - Box 50, Folder 2 (Box 50)
- Stephen Romano (b. 1957)
  Stephen Romano was born in 1957 in Boston, Massachusetts. He received a BFA from Parsons School of Design. He has worked in fashion, set design, interior design, and production for film.
  Materials pertaining to Stephen Romano were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997 by Paula Romano. They contain correspondence, exhibition announcements, CVs, an image of the artist, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1991-1997.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/stephen-romano
  - Box 50, Folder 5 (Box 50)
- James Romberger (b. 1958)
  James Romberger was born in 1958 in Port Jefferson, New York. He studied at the Munson Williams Proctor Institute, School of Visual Arts, Borough of Manhattan Community College, Columbia University, and CUNY Graduate Center. His work spans pastel drawings, comics, installation, and film work, depicting life in the Lower East Side and his experiences living there. With Marguerite Van Cook, he published 7 Miles a Second, a graphic novel memoir written in collaboration with David Wojnarowicz. His work has been exhibited widely in New York and is held in many private collections. He lives in New York City.
  James Romberger first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2005. They contain exhibition announcements, CVs, press clippings, an artist's statement, copies of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1989-2021.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/james-romberger
  - Box 50, Folder 6 (Box 50)
  - Box B, Folder 13 (Box B)
- Dyke Rowntree (1953–1988)
  Dyke Rowntree was born in 1953 in Chickasha, Oklahoma. He received a BA in art. His work includes paintings, collage, textiles, and mixed media sculpture. He passed away in 1988.
  Materials pertaining to Dyke Rowntree were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2008 by Dala Rowntree. They contain correspondence and an artist's biography. These materials are dated 2008.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/dyke-rowntree
  - Box 50, Folder 8 (Box 50)
- Craig Russell (1953–2019)
  Craig Russell was born in 1953 in Illinois. He received a BS in graphic design from Illinois State University and a multimedia certificate from Pratt Institute. His works in painting, photography, collage, digital art, and video have been exhibited in New York. He passed away in 2019.
  Craig Russell first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain exhibition announcements, images of art, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, CVs, correspondence, excerpts from children's book, press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1973-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/craig-russell
  - Box 50, Folder 10 (Box 50)
- Gregory Russell (b. 1953)
  Gregory Russell was born in 1955 in Washington, DC. He holds a BFA and MFA from Maryland Institute College of Art. He works primarily in oil painting and has exhibited across the east coast of the US and in Zimbabwe. His art is informed by his experience in community social work.
  Gregory Russell first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, artist's statements, CVs, correspondence, press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1977-2013.
  - Box 51, Folder 1 (Box 51)
- Rafael Sanchez (b. 1960)
  Rafael Sanchez was born in 1960 in Havana, Cuba. He studied at duCret School of the Arts and Rutgers University. His work includes painting, photography, sculpture, installation, film and theater, and digital art. It has been exhibited across the US and internationally.
  Rafael Sanchez first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain poetry books, CVs, exhibition materials, a play program, and memorial materials. These materials are dated 2011-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/rafael-sanchez
  - Box 51, Folder 3 (Box 51)
- Phyllis Sanfiorenzo (b. 1959)
  Phyllis Sanfiorenzo was born in 1959 in New York City. She studied at the Fashion Institute of Technology, New School, and School of Visual Arts. She works in painting and sculpture and has produced illustrations for theatre companies as well as public art.
  Phyllis Sanfiorenzo first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2015. They contain a CV and an exhibition announcement. These materials are dated 2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/phyllis-sanfiorenzo
  - Box 51, Folder 5 (Box 51)
- Carmine Santaniello (b. 1955)
  Carmine Santaniello was born in 1955 in New York. He studied at Parsons School of Design. He works in painting, print making, and collage and has exhibited in New York and internationally. His art has also been featured in many publications and is held in various permanent collections.
  Carmine Santaniello first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain correspondence, ephemera, exhibition announcements, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, artist's statements, CVs, artist's biographies, press releases, CDs with images of art, publications, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 2001-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/carmine-santaniello
  - Box 51, Folder 6 (Box 51)
  - Box 51, Folder 7 (Box 51)
- Luis Tito Santos (b. 1961)
  Luis Tito Santos was born in 1961 in New York City. He is a self-taught artist and works in painting and illustration.
  Luis Tito Santos first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain an artist's statement, an artist's biography, and images of art. These materials are dated 2001.
  - Box 51, Folder 9 (Box 51)
- Rene Santos (1954–1986)
  Rene Santos was born in 1954 in Puerto Rico. He received a BFA from Tufts University and an MFA from Hunter College. His work in photography, collage, and paintings has been exhibited in New York as well as across the US, Puerto Rico, and Europe. He passed away in 1986.
  Materials pertaining to Rene Santos were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997 by his mother. They contain correspondence, excerpts from essays, press releases, press clippings, periodicals, CVs, an exhibition catalog, image lists, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1979-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/rene-santos
  - Box 51, Folder 10 (Box 51)
  - Box 52, Folder 1 (Box 52)
- John Sapp (b. 1947)
  John Sapp was born in 1947. He received a BA from Tulane University in New Orleans, Louisiana, an MFA from the University of California Berkeley, and a JD from the University of Texas law school. He also studied painting and sculpture. He works in painting and illustration and has exhibited in Texas, California, and New York.
  Materials pertaining to John Sapp were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2005 by Corliss Cavalieri. They contain artwork on postcards, correspondence, a CV and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1988-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/john-sapp
  - Box 52, Folder 2 (Box 52)
- Richard Sawdon-Smith (b. 1963)
  Richard Sawdon Smith was born in 1963 in England. He was educated in graphic design and photography and is a professor of photography at Norwich University of the Arts. He is an award-winning photographer whose work has been exhibited and published internationally.